Okay, so we've seen the global services,
but how do we have a global application?
Well, let's discuss architecture a little bit.
So if we have a single region, single AZ, it's very simple.
We have an EC2 instance in one easy in one region
that does not give us high availability, for sure.
This does not give us good global agency,
because if we access this institution
from a user that's very, very far away
from a region is going to get bad at latency.
And it's very, very simple to set up.
So very, very low difficulty.
Next, we have a single region, multi AZ.
So here we have two AZs within one region.
So we do have high availability,
but we do not have improvements for a global agency.
So again, the AZs are close to each other.
And so if we take a point in the well
that's far away from my AZs
then we're going to have high latency.
And the difficulty is a little bit increased,
but not that much.
Next we have a multi-region called active passive.
And remember that term so active passive,
it means that we have two regions.
Each region has one or multiple AZ
and in one region our EC2 instances are going to be active,
or our application is going to be active.
That means that our users,
wherever they are in the world can do reads
and writes to our EC2 instance in the active region.
And the other one EC2 is passive.
That means that there is data replication
between the active region and the passive region.
And possibly the users can do reads from the passive region,
but they can not do writes to the passive region.
That's why it's called passive, active passive.
And so with active passive,
well, if we have many regions around the world
and they're all passive, that means
that we are going to have improved read latency
because now we have our data replicated
across the world and with low latency,
but for writes well, all the writes still need to go
to the same central region.
So that means that the writes at a global level
still have the high latency.
And finally, well, it's definitely increased difficulty
because now we have multiple regions,
so that's active passive,
and finally we have active active.
And so this is where each EC2 instance
is able to take writes and reads,
and there is replication still happening
within these two instances.
So this improves the read latency,
the write latency at a global level, obviously.
And it's higher difficulty because now your application
has to do a lot of things in every single region
and is more difficult to set up.
But for example, a database
that is having an active active demo setup
is dynamoDB global tables as we've seen before.
Okay, so if you remember just what these means,
active active, active passive, multi-region, single region,
you should be good to go for the exam
to answer one question.
All right, that's it.
I will see you in the next lecture.